welcome to the listening Time Podcast
hey everybody this is Connor and you're
listening to episode
1029 of the listening Time Podcast thank
you all for listening I hope you're all
doing well I hope that your English
learning is going great and at the time
that this episode is released it will be
the week of Thanksgiving here in the US
and so that's what I want to talk about
today I'm going to talk about
Thanksgiving I'll talk about this
holiday uh the origins of the holiday
some of the food that people like to eat
here uh on Thanksgiving and uh I'll talk
about some of the things that I'm
thankful for uh from this year from
2023 so hopefully you'll enjoy this
episode and a lot of people are curious
about Thanksgiving because it's not
something that you have all around the
world it's more of a regional thing in
the US I think in Canada I'm not sure
where else but uh you don't have
Thanksgiving uh all over the world so a
lot of people are curious about this
topic if they've never celebrated
Thanksgiving in the US before so we'll
talk about that today and and remember
that if you feel ready to practice with
real
conversations uh in which I speak to a
native speaker and we talk normally and
naturally then make sure to sign up for
my us conversations podcast I release
one new episode every month and it's a
long conversation between me and someone
else from a different part of the us and
of course you have the transcript uh for
each episode and you also have the
definitions of key words and phrases uh
that we use during the conversation so
if you're interested in that make sure
to click on the link in the episode
description below this episode that's
patreon.com USC
conversations and if you want my
training for your pronunciation and
you're listening then make sure to join
my membership so you can get my
specialized training to help you uh
pronounce English better and also listen
and understand more effectively so the
link is also in the description below
this episode and if you like this
podcast please share it with anyone else
you know who's learning English and give
it a five-star rating and write a review
all right let's get started are your
ears ready you know what time it is it's
listening
time okay let's talk about Thanksgiving
first let me talk a little bit about the
origins of Thanksgiving uh where it came
from so it's generally believed that
Thanksgiving originated in the year
1621 so what was happening at that time
well there were English settlers who we
would call
pilgrims that came over on the Mayflower
ship this was maybe the most famous ship
that went back and forth uh between uh
Europe and what is now the US right um
that went back and forth between uh
Europe and America right and so uh these
pilgrims are the people who came uh
starting in 1620 I believe and then all
throughout the 1620s they came um taking
this Mayflower ship and they established
Plymouth Colony and that's in
Massachusetts okay so this is one of the
most famous colonies that the English
settlers established in the US it was
the second per colony in America so it
was one of the most significant ones and
so these pilgrims uh who established the
Plymouth
Colony they uh were in contact with some
of the native people so specifically um
for this Thanksgiving story we're
talking about the Wampanoag people so
these are Native Americans who were here
uh prior to
uh the English settlers coming when we
say prior to something we're saying
before something so prior to the
Mayflower bringing the pilgrims over uh
these Wampanoag people were already
there and of course there was a lot of
contact between the settlers and these
Natives and in
1621 there was an Autumn Harvest f East
so uh Autumn referring to the season of
course and the Harvest referring to um
the crops that you grow uh on your land
and then you uh Harvest them and then
you can eat them uh and use them in
different ways that's the Harvest part
and then a feast a feast just refers to
a big meal that you have uh with
multiple people right so they had an
Autumn Harvest Feast um with the
pilgrims and the wamp Noak people and so
that is what most people believe uh to
be the first Thanksgiving meal was that
meal that Feast that they shared I don't
know if this is accurate and I think
that no one can say 100% for sure if
this is accurate but I think that that's
what is generally considered to be true
so that's a little bit about the first
Thanksgiving so now what is Thanksgiving
about because at that time it was an
Autumn feast and it was between two
different groups of people right um and
there was some significance to that that
the natives were eating with the
settlers and sharing this meal together
nowadays that's not uh the thing that
most people think about when they think
about Thanksgiving now Thanksgiving is
generally thought of to be a day where
you get together with your family you
eat an amazing meal and you show
gratitude for the things that you have
when we say that you show gratitude
we're saying that you express the fact
that you're thankful
for things so that's more or less what
people think about today when they think
about Thanksgiving and I want to mention
that Thanksgiving is not the most
important holiday in the US in my
opinion so I get this question all the
time or I hear people say this all the
time from other countries that I talk to
they say uh Thanksgiving seems like the
most important holiday in the US uh
they'll have this assumption and I would
definitely disagree with this I would
say that Christmas is by far the most
important holiday Thanksgiving might be
number two for a lot of people um but
it's not number one for most people so
for example I went many years without
celebrating Thanksgiving because I
didn't live near my family and I didn't
come back home for Thanksgiving and it
was sad but it wasn't um a huge deal I
wasn't completely depressed that I
wasn't celebrating Thanksgiving however
when I uh was not home for Christmas I
had to celebrate Christmas with someone
with some people because I can't imagine
not celebrating Christmas one year
however I I can uh imagine not
celebrating Thanksgiving because I
didn't celebrate it for almost a decade
so um it's not as important as Christmas
in my opinion but it's an important
holiday okay now let me talk a little
bit about some of the food that we eat
on Thanksgiving so the meal that we have
on this holiday is similar to the meal
that we have on Christmas so the dishes
are very similar and a lot of them are
the same the biggest difference is that
Thanksgiving is famous for turkey and uh
this is kind of the protagonist of the
meal for many families right this is the
main character let's say um for
Christmas some people eat turkey that's
true however I think that that it's more
common to eat ham on Christmas and this
is one of my favorite things uh during
the Christmas meal is eating ham so I
associate ham with Christmas and turkey
with Thanksgiving however the side
dishes are very similar and a lot of
them are the same so I just refer to all
of this as holiday food in the us and
this is one of the best things about
celebrating these holidays in the US uh
compared to maybe uh celebrating
Christmas in other countries because the
US has a lot of food that is uh meant
for these holidays so there is a lot of
food that's specifically linked to these
holidays and I know you have this in
other countries as well however in my
experience talking to students from
different countries and living in Mexico
for many years there usually isn't as
much specific holiday food that you only
eat during this season during the
Thanksgiving or Christmas season whereas
in the US there are a lot of dishes
where if you just say the name of the
dish immediately people think of
Christmas or they think of Thanksgiving
so that was one of my complaints when I
celebrated Christmas in Mexico is I felt
that uh there was some holiday food but
not nearly as much as in the US because
a lot of the holiday food that we ate in
Mexico is food that you might also eat
during other parts of the Year there are
some things that are definitely
associated with with Christmas however
in my experience uh not as much as um
the holiday food in the US so for
example if you think of uh the Christmas
ham uh if you see the sight of that ham
that's sliced uh in thin slices you
automatically think of Christmas or if
you see a turkey coming out of the oven
then you automatically think of
Thanksgiving and there are other dishes
like this as well for example stuffing
so this is kind of a wet bread pudding
uh I guess you could call it that
traditionally was stuffed inside the
turkey uh to cook with the turkey
however you don't need to do that uh and
uh I've read that it can actually be
dangerous if uh you don't do it
correctly but that's where the name
comes from stuffing right it was stuffed
in the meat of the turkey so if someone
says the word stuffing you immediately
think of Thanksgiving usually another
one is cranberry sauce there's this
special sauce that um it it's really
delicious and it kind of enhances the
other dishes the word enhance refers to
making something better uh and so when I
say that the cranberry sauce enhances
other dishes I'm saying that you can eat
the cranberry sauce with these other
side dishes or with the turkey and it uh
creates a really delicious combination I
like eating turkey with this cranberry
sauce so that's a really tasty combo in
my opinion and then with the turkey
there is white meat and dark meat so I
prefer dark meat because it has more
flavor um but some people like white
meat so the turkey has both it has white
meat and dark meat and people will
normally ask you do you want white or
dark right in my opinion if you eat
White meat then you should pair it with
this cranberry sauce when I say that you
pair something with something else this
means that you um put the two things
together so I think that the white meat
can be a little bit dry and without a
lot of flavor so I like to pair it with
the cranberry sauce and this enhances
the uh experience the the flavor of the
turkey so cranberry sauce is another one
that people will immediately associate
with Thanksgiving usually and another
one could be sweet potato casserole this
is one of my favorite dishes because
it's not a
dessert however it's sweet so it's kind
of an interesting side dish where you
have these sweet potatoes which are are
in general sweet right um and then you
can also put things like uh brown sugar
or marshmallows or things like that um
that can make it even sweeter uh if you
don't know what a marshmallow is this is
that white uh soft food that you usually
roast over a fire when you're camping
this is a marshmallow so some people add
marshmallows to the this sweet potato
casserole and it's really delicious I've
never had a bad sweet potato casserole
it's kind of hard to go wrong with this
dish so that's another one where if you
say that people immediately think of
Thanksgiving or Christmas and one other
one that I like is green bean casserole
so this is another casserole that you
bake in the oven and uh it's with green
beans and other things usually this is
uh associated with holidays with
Thanksgiving and Christmas so that's
another one and then there are other
dishes that we can have uh at other
times during the year but they're also
very um uh related to these two holidays
so for example um mashed potatoes and
gravy you can eat that anytime
throughout the year however um it's hard
hard for me to imagine a Thanksgiving
meal without mashed potatoes and without
gravy so that's one that's not uh just
particular to Thanksgiving however I
can't imagine Thanksgiving without it
and there are other things like dinner
rolls uh a roll in this context refers
to uh a piece of bread it's usually
really fluffy on the inside it's soft
and delicious uh you add butter to it um
it's really good my mouth is watering
just thinking about it by the way when
we say that your mouth is watering we're
saying that you are salivating your uh
mouth is producing saliva because you're
imagining eating something we say your
mouth is watering and one of the most
popular desserts uh that we eat during
Thanksgiving is pie things like pumpkin
pie pecan pie apple pie we have tons of
different pies um that's one of my
favorite desserts uh that we eat during
Thanksgiving and there are many other uh
dishes that are associated with
Thanksgiving or with Christmas um those
are just a handful uh of them and uh
some of my favorites and now I want to
talk a little bit about what I'm
thankful for this year because on
Thanksgiving it's good to Express
gratitude it's good to say what you're
thankful for and to reflect on these
blessings that you have in your life so
there are many things that I thank God
for this year uh that uh I just really
appreciate uh one of the things that
comes to mind is uh the end of my wife's
immigration process so uh at the very
end of last year we finished uh the
immigration process for my wife and this
year is the year that uh we have
established ourselves um in the US me
being a citizen and she being a resident
so we had been waiting for that process
to end for so long uh we
constantly thought about the immigration
process and it was often stressful to
have to um wait and go through the next
step in the process and then wait and
then have to uh travel for an interview
and do all of these different things and
we hated that feeling of not being sure
where we were going to live in the
future and just being
in this process and so when she finally
finished the process and we moved up
here uh this was a huge relief for us
the word relief refers to that feeling
that you get when um you were feeling
bad and then now that's gone away you
feel relief so this year is our first
year uh living in the us legally and we
can start to establish ourselves here
and I'm extremely thankful that we got
through that process and that uh we're
now living here um this year has been uh
a a really great year being able to be
up in the US have my wife here have my
son here and that leads me to my next uh
thing that I'm really thankful for this
year is that I've been able to spend a
lot of time with my parents and with my
sister and her family so they all live
in the US and so when I lived in Mexico
all those years it was hard for me to
see them on a regular basis and so now
this year has been the first time uh
when all of us can get together and uh
watch our kids grow up together and do
all of that it's a big blessing for me I
was really um looking forward to uh
being able to do this uh at some point
and now this year we can do it so I'm
very happy about that I'm very happy to
be with my parents uh as I've mentioned
before my mom has very severe health
issues and so it's been really great to
be with her here and to help out a
little bit and uh that's been awesome
and of course spending time with my dad
and uh seeing my nephew and now my new
niece because my sister just gave birth
to another kid so I get to be part of my
nephew and my niece's life and that's
really cool so I'm very thankful for
that and I'm very thankful for my own
family for my wife for my son it's been
great to watch him grow up more this
year it's been great to watch him
develop and start to talk and uh do all
of those cool things uh that's been a
huge blessing uh it's been great to uh
be able to do fun things with my wife
and my son uh up here in the US so I'm
thankful for my own family I'm thankful
for my church uh I have a church up here
that I really like and uh the members
are awesome and uh that's a big part uh
of my life and it's something that I'm
very thankful for uh it's something that
I can't uh go without uh when you go
without something we're saying that you
don't have it you uh don't use or have
something
and just continue without that so I
can't go without that I'm really
thankful for my church as well uh I'm
really thankful for my job so I've been
able to reach a lot of people with this
content and I've received uh many many
messages uh from people thanking me for
uh helping them and providing this
content that's been useful for their
listening practice
and of course my membership which has
helped a lot of people start to um
understand the sounds of English and
understand native speakers better and
pronounce things better so I'm very
thankful that I've been able to develop
uh this uh my career and be able to help
a lot of people with this free content
and also the
content and uh it's really cool to have
a job like that where you're helping
multiple people um it's great to help
one person but it's uh even cooler in my
opinion to help more than one person so
I've been really thankful for that that
I still have this uh job this activity
that I can live on and um that's been a
big blessing and and one other thing
that I'm really thankful for this year
is my audience all of you uh as I
already mentioned I receive a lot of
messages from you I can't respond to all
of them unfortunately because they come
at me from different angles some from
different social media uh platforms and
I'm not the best person at um viewing
all my messages and you've probably seen
that by now that I'm not the most
connected person on social media or
whatever however I want to thank all of
you um those of you that send me
messages and just all of you for
listening uh for helping me do what I do
um the fact that I have listeners from
all over the world um is really cool it
motivates me to continue doing this and
uh of course for those of you that uh
are members of my membership uh I really
appreciate your support and for those of
you that have signed up for my new
podcast I really appreciate you as well
so I'm thankful for all of you I'm
thankful for my audience I wanted to say
that here uh because it's important for
me to express that especially during
this episode about Thanksgiving so thank
you all again um and I'm thankful for
many more things as well but those were
just uh a few that I wanted to mention
all right well that's it for today I
hope that this episode was interesting
for you I hope that if you're in the US
or Canada or wherever and you're
celebrating Thanksgiving this week that
you have a great Thanksgiving with your
family or your friends and uh I hope
that you can reflect on some of the
things that you're thankful for as well
and remember that if you need more help
uh if you need my specialized training
to understand uh native speakers better
or to pronounce uh more correctly then
make sure to join my membership and
you'll get my specialized training and
if you're ready for real conversations
if you want to practice with real
English between native speakers then
make sure to sign up for my us
conversations podcast and you'll get a
new conversation every month with the
transcript and with the definitions of
keywords so the link to that is down
below that's
patreon.com us conversations and if you
like this podcast I'd really appreciate
it if you could share it with different
people you know who are learning English
and please give it a five-star rating
and write a review if you can all right
thank you so much for listening to this
episode and I'll talk to you on the next
episode of listening
[Music]
time